<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Looking at SRS files with Pilatus Images">
	<intro>
		<description>
			This Tutorial will show you how to view SRS files which contain Pilatus Images
		</description>
	</intro>
	<item title="Open DEXplore Perspective">
		<command required="true"
			serialization="org.eclipse.ui.perspectives.showPerspective(org.eclipse.ui.perspectives.showPerspective.perspectiveId=uk.ac.diamond.scisoft.dataexplorationperspective)"/>
		<description>
			To visualise data effectively the DExplore Perspective is the best perspective to use,
			change to this now.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Open A Pilatus Scan">
		<description>
			Navigate to an example Pilatus SRS data using either the Project Explorer or file navigator.
<br/><br/>
Single click or select the file and you should see the <b>Header</b> view in the bottom right corner of the perspective fill with all the metadata from this file.
			<br/><br/>
			In the Header view there is a filter box at the top, which is useful for finding specific values in a large body of metadata. For example typing <b>UB</b> into the box
will list of all the metadata which has UB in the key (i.e. the 9 elements of the UB matrix).
			<br/><br/>
Now Double Click on the file to open it for displaying the data.
			<br/><br/>
			The file should open in the Editor area (previously blank) and show a list
			of all the datasets which are in this file, plus some information about them.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Plotting the Data From the File">
		<description>
			To plot some simple data from the file, simply click on the name of the data which you
would like to see and the data will be shown in the Dataset Plot.
			<br/><br/>
If there is default x-axis data associated with the file, this will be picked up and used. If there is no default x-axis data (or the &quot;plot first dataset as x-axis&quot; is not checked), the selected data will be plotted against a default &apos;dim&apos; axis, which is simply a count of the points in the plot. The required x-axis data can be changed by selecting the values in the &quot;Data Axes Selection&quot; table.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Plotting the Pilatus Data">
		<description>
			At the bottom of the list of available data there will be an element called <b>Pilatus</b>. The Extra information about this will be tagged as &apos;Not Available&apos; due to the fact that this
			could be a lot of data, and we only load it off disk when it is needed, so values such
			as these cannot be calculated. Select this element now.
			<br/><br/>
			A new plot should have appeared, and the <b>Dataset Inspector</b> should now be reporting that the data it has
			access to is 3 dimensional. This means we can select to view the information in a
			variety of ways.
			<br/><br/>
			To look at the images which have been collected you need to change
			to the 2D image mode in the <b>Dataset Inspector</b>. This is done by selecting the
			<b>2D image tab</b> in the top right section of the view, you may need to expand the
			options if you cannot see it immediately by using the &apos;&gt;&gt;&apos; part to the right of
			existing tabs.
			<br/><br/>
			The Pilatus Image should now have appeared in the Dataset Plot. To change which Image
			is being viewed, you can use the dataset slicing section at the bottom of the <b>Dataset
			Inspector</b> view. If the dataset contains more than one image there will be one Slicer bar which is not fully across. Drag this bar about, and you will see the image change in the <b>Dataset Plot</b> view.	</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Advanced Slicing">
		<description>
			So far we have only done the simplest of slicing, and it is important to realise that
			there is much more functionality available.  The 3D pilatus datasets can be sliced as 1D line plots or 2D image plots along any axis of the cube.
			<br/><br/>
			There are also other ways of slicing, which can be explored, and the more you use it the more functionality becomes apparent. You should be aware though that slicing against
			the way the data was collected can sometimes take a long time as
			the storage systems are not optimised to do this kind of operation.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Surface Plotting">
		<description>
			Finally lets look at one other way of plotting the data. Instead of '2D image' tab,
			select '2D Surface'
			<br/><br/>
			The same tools are available, just you are now viewing a surface plot, and not an image.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Done">
		<description>
			This tutorial has taken you through some basics of looking at SRS data which contains
			embedded Pilatus Data. But remember that the slicing and visualisation tools used here
			would work on any multidimensional dataset, and work especially well with NeXus files.
		</description>
	</item>
</cheatsheet>
